Guide to the Casey Recordings, 1944-1985 CASEY.2001
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Classical, 1945-1948, 1962, 1965, 1967, 1971-1973, 1975, 1980; II.
  - Schumann "Rhenish" Symphony, No. 3 in E-Flat, Op. 97 (Record CAS CLA 0072)
    This album consists of 4 discs with 2 sides each. Disc 1 side (A) includes 1. Allegro (Part 1). Side (B) includes 5. Finale: Allegro (conc.).
    Disc 2 side (A) includes 1. Allegro (Part 2). Side (B) includes (A) 4. Grave (conc.) (B) 5. Finale: Allegro.
    Disc 3 side (A) includes 1. Allegro (conc.). Side (B) includes 4. Grave (Part 1).
    Disc 4 side (A) includes 2. Scherzo: Allegretto. Side (B) includes 3. Moderato. This album also includes program notes by Hall, David inside cover.
  - Kindler, Hans (cello) with Bourdon, Rosario (piano); Träumerei; A Dream (Record CAS CLA 0072.1)
    This album consists of 1 disc with 2 sides. Side (A) includes Träumerei. Side (B) includes A Dream.
  - SIBELIUS Symphony No. 7, in C Major, Op. 105. A Victor Musical Masterpiece (Record CAS CLA 0073)
    This album consists of 3 discs with 2 sides each. Disc 1 side (A) includes Symphony No. 7 in C Major, Op. 105 (Part 1). Side (B) includes Symphony No. 7 in C Major, Op. 105 (conc.).
    Disc 2 side (A) includes Symphony No. 7 in C Major, Op. 105 (Part 2). Side (B) includes Symphony No. 7 in C Major, Op. 105 (Part 5).
    Disc 3 side (A) includes Symphony No. 7 in C Major, Op. 105 (Part 3). Side (B) includes Symphony No. 7 in C Major, Op. 105 (Part 4). This album also includes list of "ceiling prices" inside cover.
  - Richard Strauss Burlesque in D Minor, Carl Maria von Weber Konzertstück in F Minor, Op. 79 (Record CAS CLA 0074)
    This album consists of 4 discs with 2 sides each. Disc 1 side (A) includes Burlesque In D Minor (Part 1). Side (B) includes Tempo di marcia (conc.).
    Disc 2 side (A) includes Burlesque In D Minor (Part 2). Side (B) includes (A) Adagio (B) Tempo di marcia (Part 1).
    Disc 3 side (A) includes Burlesque In D Minor (Part 3). Side (B) includes Allegro passionato.
    Disc 4 side (A) includes Burlesque In D Minor (conc.). Side (B) includes Larghetto affettuoso. This album also includes program notes by Hall, David inside cover.
  - Tchaikovksy Concerto in D, for Violin and Orchestra (Record CAS CLA 0075)
    This album consists of 4 discs with 2 sides each. Disc 1 side (A) includes 1. Allegro Moderato (Part 1). Side (B) includes 3. Allegro vivacissimo (conc.).
    Disc 2 side (A) includes 1. Allegro Moderato (Part 2). Side (B) includes 3. Allegro vivacissimo (Part 2).
    Disc 3 side (A) includes 1. Allegro Moderato (Part 3). Side (B) includes (A) 2. Canzonetta: Andante (conc.) (B) Allegro vivacissimo (Part 1).
    Disc 4 side (A) includes 1. Allegro Moderato (conc.). Side (B) includes 2. Canzonetta: Andante (Part 1). This album also includes program notes by Hall, David inside cover.
  - Celestina Boninsegna sings O cieli azzuri from Verdi's Opera Aida (recorded in 1906) and Ma dall' arido stelo divulsa from Verdi's Opera Un Ballo in Maschera (recorded in 1906), 1947 (Record CAS CLA 0076)
    This album consists of 1 disc with 2 sides. Side (A) includes O cieli azzuri. Side (B) includes Ma dall' arido stelo divulsa. The album is in a gold cover.
  - Pasquale Amato sings O Vecchio cor, che batti from Verdi's Opera I Due Foscari and Ferito Prigionier from Franchetti's Opera Germania, 1947 (Record CAS CLA 0077)
    This album consists of 1 disc with 2 sides. Side (A) includes O Vecchio cor, che batti. Side (B) includes Ferito Pregionier. This album is in a gold cover and was recorded in 1913.
  - Otello: Act IV (Record CAS CLA 0078)
    This album consists of 1 disc with 2 sides. Side (A) includes Salce, Salce. Side (B) includes Ave Maria. This album was recorded in 1910.
  - Bachianas Brasileiras (Record CAS CLA 0079)
    This album consists of 1 disc with 2 sides. Side (A) includes Bachianas Brasileiras, No. 5. Aria - Cantilena (Beginning) Sung In Portuguese. Side (B) includes Bachianas Brasileiras, No. 5. Aria - Cantilena (Conclusion) Sung In Portuguese. Album duplicates John Harvith 0044-0045.
  - Brünnhilde's Immolation from Wager's The Twilight of the Gods (Record CAS CLA 0080)
    This album consists of 3 discs with 2 sides each. Disc 1 side (A) includes Brünnhilde's Immolation (Part 1). Side (B) includes Liebestod.
    Disc 2 side (A) includes Brünnhilde's Immolation (Part 2). Side (B) includes Brünnhilde's Immolation (conc.).
    Disc 3 side (A) includes Brünnhilde's Immolation (Part 3). Side (B) includes Brünnhilde's Immolation (Part 4). Disc 1 is chipped. Album also includes text and translation on inside cover. Album also includes WRONG booklet with program notes (from another recording of the same work)
  - Der Meistersinger: Act I; Act III (Record CAS CLA 0080.1)
    This album consists of 1 disc with 2 sides. Side (A) includes Am Stillen Herd. Side (B) includes Preislied.
  - Wagner Tristan and Isolde: Prelude-Liebesnacht-Liebestod. A Victor Musical Masterpiece (Record CAS CLA 0081)
    This album consists of 5 discs, the first of which has 1 side while the rest have 2 sides each. Disc 1 includes Prelude (Part 1).
    Disc 2 side (A) includes Prelude (Part 2). Side (B) includes Liebestod and Conclusion.
    Disc 3 side (A) includes Prelude (conc.). Side (B) includes Liebestod (Part 2).
    Disc 4 side (A) includes Liebesnacht (Part 1). Side (B) includes Liebestod (Part 1).
    Disc 5 side (A) includes Liebesnacht (Part 2). Side (B) includes Liebesnacht (Part).
  - Wagner: Die Walküre-Act III (complete) (Record CAS CLA 0082)
    This album consists of 8 discs with 2 sides each. Disc 1 side (A) includes Scene 1 (beg.): Walkürenritt. Side (B) includes Scene 3 (conc.): Feuerzauber: "Wer meines Speeres Spitze fürchtet."
    Disc 2 side (A) includes Scene 1 (cont.): "In Wald mit den Rossen." Side (B) includes Scene 3 (cont.): Wotans Abschied:"Loge hör!"
    Disc 3 side (A) includes Scene 1 (cont.): "Bethörte Schwester, was thatest du?" Side (B) includes Scene 3 (cont.): Wotans Abschied: "Der Augen leuchtendes Paar."
    Disc 4 side (A) includes (A) Scene 1 (conc.): "Fort denn Eile" (B) Scene 2 (beg.): "Wo ist Brünnhilde?" Side (B) includes Scene 3 (cont.): Wotans Abschied: "Leb, wohl, du künnes, herrliches Kind!"
    Disc 5 side (A) includes Scene 2 (cont.): "Se wisst denn." Side (B) includes Scene 3 (cont.): "Nicht streb' o Maid."
    Disc 6 side (A) includes Scene 2 (cont.): "Du verstössest mich?" Side (B) includes Scene 3 (cont.): "Wohl taugte dir nicht die thör'ge Maid."
    Disc 7 side (A) includes Scene 2 (conc.) "Schreckt euch ihr Loos?" Side (B) includes Scene 3 (cont.): "So thatest du, was so gern zu thin ich begehrt."
    Disc 8 side (A) includes Scene 3 (beg.): "War es so schmählich, vas ich verbrach?" Side (B) includes Scene 3 (cont.): "Ich wusste den Zwiespatt." This album also includes program notes by Affelder, Paul.
  - Belshazzar's Feast by William Walton (Record CAS CLA 0083)
    This album consists of 2 discs with 2 sides each. Disc 1 side (A) includes Thus Spake Isaiah. Side (B) includes Then Sing Aloud (conc.).
    Disc 2 side (A) includes Praise Ye, The God of Gold. Side (B) includes Praise Ye The Gods. Both records are chipped. The set is missing records 2, 3, and 4. This album also includes text on inside cover.
  - Beethoven: The Ninth Symphony, 1973 (Record CAS CLA 0084)
    This album consists of 1 disc with 2 sides. Side (A) includes Symphony No. 9 in D Minor, op. 125 "Choral": (A) I: Allegro ma non troppo, un poco Maestoso (B) II: Molto vivace; Presto (C) III: Adagio molto e cantabile (beg.).
    Side (B) includes Symphony No. 9 in D Minor, op. 125 "Choral": (A) III: Adagio molto e cantabile (conc.) (B) Presto; Allegro assai; Rezitativo. This album also includes program notes and NY Times review on cover.
  - Debussy's Biggest Hits-Munch/Reiner/Pennario/Weissenberger, 1972 (Record CAS CLA 0085)
    This album consists of 1 disc with 2 sides. Side (A) includes Clair de lune; The Girl with the Flaxen Hair; Rêverie; Prelude to the Afternoon of a Faun.
    Side (B) includes Golliwog's Cakewalk; Nocturne: Fêtes; The Sunken Cathedral; La Mer: Dialogue of the Wind and the Waves. This album also includes program notes by McAdoo, Dale on album cover.
  - Arthur Fielder & The Best of the Boston Pops, Vol. 1, 1975 (Record CAS CLA 0086)
    This album consists of 1 disc with 2 sides. Side (A) includes (A) Saber Dance (from "Gayne" Ballet) (B) Overture to "Candide" (C) 1812 Overture, Op. 49.
    Side (B) includes (A) Toccata and Fugue in D minor (B) Night on Bald Mountain (C) The Stars and Sripes Forever. This album also includes program notes by Jones, Robert T. on album cover.
  - The Best of Arthur Fiedler and the Boston Pops, 1965 (Record CAS CLA 0087)
    This album consists of 1 disc with 2 sides. Side (A) includes Jalousie; On the Trail; More; The Glow Worm; The Yellow Rose of Texas; Prayer of Thanksgiving.
    Side (B) includes I Want to Hold Your Hand; Hello, Dolly!; Mack the Knife; Warsaw Concerto; Blue Tango; National Emblem March.
  - James Galway: Mozart Concerto for Flute & Orchestra No. 1, Concerto for Flute & Orchestra No. 2, 1973 (Record CAS CLA 0088)
    This album consists of 1 disc with 2 sides. Side (A) includes Concerto For Flute and Orchestra No. 1 in G, K313. Side (B) includes Concerto For Flute and Orchestra No. 2 in D, K314. This album also includes program notes by Quigly, Anthony on album cover.
  - Gregorian Treasures, Album No. 4. In Tribute to Mother Josephine D. Morgan, 1962 (Record CAS CLA 0089)
    This album consists of 1 disc with 2 sides. Side (A) includes 1. Introit: Ps. 80:17; 2. Kyrie 4; 3. Gradual: Ps. 144:15-16; 4. Alleluia: John 6:56-57; 5. Offertory: Lev. 21:6; 6. Sanctus IV; 7. Agnus Dei IV; 8. Communion: I Cor. 11:26-27.
    Side (B) includes 1. Introit: Ps. 36:30-31; 2. Kyrie I; 3. Gloria X; 4. Gradual: Ps. 91:13, 14, 3; 5. Alleluia: James 1:12; 6. Offertory: Ps. 88:25; 7. Sanctus XII; Agnus Dei XII; 9. Communion: Matt. 24:46-47; 10. Exposition of The Blessed Sacrament. This album also includes Latin and English translations of the Proper.
  - Immaculata College Glee Club 1966-67, 1967 (Record CAS CLA 0090)
    This album consists of 1 disc with 2 sides. Side (A) includes Exultate Deo; Mon Couer se Recommande a Vous; Scandello; Tschesnokoff; Mendelsohn; Mozart.
    Side (B) includes Ave Maria; Three Hungarian Folk Songs; Set Down Servant; O Dear! What Can the Matter Be?; Zing! Went the Strings of My Heart. This album also includes program notes in album sleeve.
  - Pavarotti's Greatest Hits, 1980 (Record CAs CLA 0091)
    This album consists of 2 discs with 2 sides each. Disc 1 side (A) includes Turandot: Nessum dorma; La Fille du Régiment: O mes amis…pour mon âmes; Tosca: Recondita armonia; La Boheme: Che gelida manina; Der Rosekavelier: Di rigori armato; Mattinata; La Danza.
    Disc 1 side (B) includes Torna a Surriento; La Favorita: Spirto gentil; Carmen: Flower Song; I Puritani: A te o cara; Il Trovatore: Di qual tetra…Ah, si ben mio; Il Trovatore: Di quella pira.
    Disc 2 side (A) includes Rigoletto: La donna è mobile; Panis Angelicus; Vanne, O Rose Fortunata; Faust: Salut! Demeure; Requiem: Ingemisco; Rigoletto: Questo e quella; Aida: Celeste Aida.
    Disc 2 side (B) includes Ave Maria; Pagliacci: Vesta la giubba; La Gioconda: Cielo e mar; L'Elisir d'Amore: Una furtiva lagrima; Tosca: E lucevan le stelle; Funiculi, Funiculà. This album also includes program notes by Fitgerald, Gerald on album cover.
  - Prokofiev: First Violin Concerto--Lalo: Symphonie Espagnole (Record CAS CLA 0092)
    This album consists of 1 disc with 2 sides. Side (A) includes Concerto No. 1 in D Major. Side (B) includes Symphonie Espagnole. This album also includes program notes on cover.
  - Concerto in D Minor for Violin and Orchestra, op. 47 (Record CAS CLA 0093)
    This album consists of 1 disc with 2 sides. Side (A) includes (A) I: Allegro moderato (B) II: Adagio di molto. Side (B) includes (A) III: Allegro, ma non tanto (B) The Swan of Tuonela. This album also includes program notes on cover and 1977 Columbia catalog in sleeve.
  - The Tchaikosky Ballet Album: The Philadelphia Orchestra/Ormandy (Record CAS CLA 0094)
    This album consists of 2 discs with 2 sides each. Disc 1 side (A) includes The Nutcracker Ballet, Op. 71 (Excerpts). Side (B) includes The Nutcracker Ballet, Op. 71 (Excerpts).
    Disc 2 side (A) includes Swan Lake Ballet Suite. Side (B) includes The Sleeping Beauty Ballet Suite. This album also includes program notes inside cover.
  - Immortal Performances: Horowitz-Toscanini Historic 1941 Recording of Tchaikovsky Piano Concerto, 1971 (Record CAS CLA 0095)
    This album consists of 1 disc with 2 sides. Side (A) includes I. Allegro non troppo e molto maestoso; Allegro con spirito. Side (B) includes (A) II. Andantino semplice; Prestissimo; Tempo I (B) III. Allegro con fuoco. This album also includes program notes by Chasins, Abram on album cover.